<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?><rss version='2.0' xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'><channel>


<title>Kokorobot</title>
<link><![CDATA[https://kokorobot.ca/]]></link>
<description>Kokorobot— personal site of Rekka Bellum</description>
 <image>
<url>https://kokorobot.ca/media/services/rss.jpg</url>
<title>Kokorobot</title>
<link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
</image>

<item>
  <title>American Sign Language Alphabet</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/asl.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Chase</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/interface/asl.jpg"><p>The one-handed American sign language alphabet is a set of 26 manual alphabetical letters, corresponding to the English alphabet. It is used to fingerspell a string of the alphabetical letters of a certain English word, person's name, etc</p><p>I drew the hand poses as reference, and practice! Ever since I incorporated a bit of ASL in my comic <a href='https://kokorobot/site/hakum.html' target='_blank'>Hakum</a> I've been obssessed with learning new words. The part of the comic that has ASL is not out yet, but I can't wait to share it (see preview below)!</p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/stories/hakum/liskar/preview.png">]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>The Chase</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/chase.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Chase</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/stories/hakum/chase/preview.png"><p>I have finished another comic sequence for <a href='https://kokorobot/site/hakum.html' target='_blank'>Hakum</a> called <a href='https://kokorobot/site/chase.html' target='_blank'>Chase</a>. Because I've had a hard time sticking with comic as a format, I've basically decided to just finish the bits that I like, in the order that I like. It will be weird for others to read, but that's how it's going to be (haha). The story will come together in the right order overtime. Anyway, I've got a good rhythm going on and I am truly in love with inking these comics with a dip pen, it is a game changer for me. I've spent the last few weeks working on some artwork for <a href='https://mindtwisted.com/' target='_blank'>Kanji Study</a>, a Kanji-learning app developed by my good friend Chasefir, I'll link the art here once it is released.</p>]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Hakum</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Hakum</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/stories/hakum/main.png" width="500"><p>Pino is back in Victoria, and so I was able to look for a scanner to scan the work I've done this summer! I found a used CanoScan LiDE 20 and I've been scanning art with it for the comic project <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html">Hakum</a>. For those who followed the project <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/circa.html" target="_blank">Circa</a>, you'll see that Hakum uses some of the same characters, that is because Circa was a sort of pilot project, a way for me to explore what sort of comic I wanted to do (a way to flesh out the story/characters). Many of the characters have changed, in both appearance and personality (its why I've nuked all the profiles in <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/characters.html" target="_blank">characters</a>, I'll add new ones soon). The story and its focus has changed too! Because it's somewhat different, I've changed the story name. I've a sketchbook-full of art to paste together, something that will occupy much of my time this winter. I've inked, scanned and processed a short segment called <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/reunited.html" target="_blank">reunited</a>.</p><p>I also finished a new rabbit tour pic for <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderrabbits.html" target="_blank"</a>Wunderland Rabbits</a>.</p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/wunderland/wunderland.9.png" width="500"><p>See full image <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/wunderland/wunderland.9.full.jpg" target="_blank">here</a>.</a></p>]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Couple illustration</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/couple.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Couple illustration</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/couple/project.couple.07.jpg" width="500"><p>Once in a while I get illustration requests for birthdays, wedding anniversaries... etc. Because I started this in mid-August, we still had power restrictions (small battery bank at anchor with limited solar), and so I was using Obi, my low power work station which runs Manjaro. I usually produce this type of illustration in Krita, but Krita doesn't work on Manjaro (at least not on mine, it crashes). I wondered then if I could use Gimp and get a similar result. I like Gimp, it is useful for simple image processing, but painting in it is not easy.</p><p>When I started painting, there was some friction, but in the end I got the result I wanted. Gimp doesn't have a slider for brush size or opacity, and brush options are... limited. I found a sketchy, elongated brush that worked well enough. Anyway, this is the result. Not bad at all.</p><p>This illustration is for Andrew Thorp. The above image is cropped, view the full art <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/couple/project.couple.07.full.jpg" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
  </p><p><a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/couple.html" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Hello Kid Rek</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Hello Kid Rek</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/sketch/kidrek1.jpg" width="500"><p>Hello Kid Rek, we haven't talked in a while. I wanted to tell you that the last two and a half months have been my most productive, drawing wise, since when I was your age. We used to fill sketchbooks so fast that we started numbering them, remember? That was a great time. But I'm sad to say that as we got older and started to draw for a living our output of personal works lessened, and was almost brought to a complete halt. Me, now-adult Rek, hasn't owned a sketchbook in years, relying instead on stray pieces of paper, small notebooks and digital sketches. I've never stopped drawing entirely, but I've stopped diving into the worlds that we'd made together, and loved. The characters were always on my mind, but I could never put them to paper. I'd resigned myself to the idea that they could only live in my head, and that somehow it was enough... this is all I could get. I did try and fill other new, blank sketchbooks after that, but never felt the same drive as back then, and the sketchbooks ended mostly unused, and eventually turned into objects of guilt. I've always assumed that drawing with such energy and passion was something I could only ever do as you, Kid Rek, that this time was over, gone, and that I could not get it back. But this year, I'm not sure why I did it, but after a 12-year gap I bought a new sketchbook. I did let it sit on the shelf for a time, with some trepidation, wondering when it too would start to throw guilt my way. I drew a commission on the first page, and hoped that it wouldn't be the only drawing that would ever populate its pages. I became superstitious, as if the mere act of thinking that I would not fill this sketchbook would turn into another 12-year long curse. Devine and I left the dock with <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/pino.html" target="_blank">Pino</a> in early May 2022, and now, I'm delighted to say Kid Rek, that this same sketchbook, after a few weeks, is already nearly filled with drawings from cover to cover.</p><p>What happened? I've always felt guilty spending my days drawing comics that are destined primarily for me, for us. "It's not productive," I'd say to myself, "you love it, and it animates you like nothing else, but it's not going to earn you money." For that reason I've long ignored my wants, in favor of supposed self-imposed 'had-tos'. In the summer, we lie at anchor full-time and don't have moorage to pay... and so somehow, I feel the guilt less. (I live on a boat Kid Rek, you would have never guessed that, right?) This is also my first real Pacific Northwest summer on the boat (you've left the cold Montreal winters too, impressed yet?), with no destination, few projects or concerns. This is free time, and because it is my mind is unbothered by thoughts of money and is free to roam and play... all day, like we used to to do. I did feel some guilt in the start, but it slowly ebbed away... and with every passing day I felt its pull less and less until it was gone almost entirely. Now I realize how much I need this in my life. I spend my days having sometimes pleasant, sometimes difficult conversations with fictional characters, with myself. I look to the conversations of the previous day with satisfaction. Playing out situations, different characters with different motives, backgrounds and beliefs, is nourishing my mind, I've found it to be a good way to digest information, and to develop empathy.</p><p>I've always enjoyed making free-form comics. By free-form, I mean not bound by timelines, or borders. I illustrate the moments I want, withhold others. This is what I want for my wiki, to share a story across different mediums. Some bits are better by text, other by comics, or maybe animation (this is me getting ahead of myself). For now, I am filling pages, inking them as I go with plans to digitize them in the fall/winter. When I draw, I catch myself smiling, laughing a lot. I am having a very good time right now, Kid Rek, you'd be proud. </p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/sketch/kidrek2.jpg" width="500"><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/sketch/kidrek3.jpg" width="500"><p>See <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/updates.html" target="_blank">past updates</a>.</p>.]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Alder IT</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/illustration.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Alder IT</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/illustration/illustration.alderit.full.jpg" width="500"><p>Gideon from Alder IT contacted me a few months ago, with the goal of making small assets for their website. They are 'rooted' in their community, and want to offer services to local businesses.</p><p>The overall goal was to incorporate local flora, along with a computer to put an emphasis on this relationship, but to keep nature as the focus. So I drew an alder tree, along with some dandelions, common blue violets and crocuses. </p>
    <img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/sketch/illustration.alderit.concept.jpg" width="500">
    <p>Gideon requested a tree growing from the computer, so I tried a ton of variations on that. We ended up going with #4, but I quite like #5,9 and 12 too. An old-style, boxey computer works well for logos, I liked the idea of a garden growing overtop, but computers no longer look like that and it is rather silly to use for a modern company. #9, conceptually, was my favorite, with a screen mountain on a little floating island, the bracket holding the screen becomes the trunk of the tree on screen, and then the tree breaks out of the screen overtop.</p><p>Gideon & I also really liked #12, with someone sitting with a keyboard on the ground, with a screen embedded into a tree with no visible wiring. I drew this after watching a documentary about <a href='https://www.edutopia.org/blog/self-organized-learning-sugata-mitra' target='_blank'>hole in the wall computers</a> in India.</p>
    <img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/sketch/illustration.alderit.concept2.jpg" width="500">
    <p>So Gideon chose #4, and I drew a detailed version. Because it is a detailed design, we opted to make two logos, with a larger one suitable for print (pictured above, on the left), and another smaller, simplified version for business cards (pictured above, on the right). I drew the large version of the logo on a grid, and made a smaller scale version of that same-sized grid to make the smaller version of the logo. I could have eyeballed it, but I liked knowing the details are placed exactly the same.</p>
  </p><p><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/illustration.html'>Read more</a>.]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Pufferfish logo</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/illustration.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Pufferfish logo</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/illustration/illustration.puffer.full.jpg" width="500"><p><a href='https://j3s.sh/' target='_blank'>Jes Olson</a> contacted me recently to make a pufferfish logo. I'd never drawn a pufferfish. I enjoyed it so much that I drew many (maybe too many).</p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/sketch/pufferfish_sketchbook.jpg" width="500"><p>The largest pufferfish in the top image was the final result. At the start I thought Jes wanted a more realistic one, which explains some of the kimokawaii designs (haha). Many of them I didn't expect to be accepted as a logo as is, but I thought to publish them here because they were part of the process. They were exploratory designs which led to the final one. As I draw something for the first time, I think 'what makes a pufferfish look like a pufferfish?'. I tried to pack in as much details as I could to figure that out, but really what makes a pufferfish a pufferfish are the spines, the fins and the round body. So, I toned down some of the realism, removed details, simplified the design.</p><p>I think it is nice to share the process, because it is rare to come up with the final idea right away. My first sketches are almost always off-mark, unless I know the person asking for the drawing really well. It isn't a failure on my part, or theirs, it is just part of figuring out what the person wants and what makes the best possible design. I am super happy with te final puffer design, and I think Jes is too!</p>
  </p><p><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/illustration.html'>Read more</a>.]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Bicycle</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/uxn.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Bicycle</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/uxn/11.jpg" width="500"><p>Drew Varvara on a Sinclair bicycle for Devine's interactive Uxntal playground named <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/bicycle.html' target'_blank'>Bicycle</a>. Drawn/inked on paper, photographed and cleaned up in GIMP.</p><p>I had a very brief drawing funk this week, am glad to say I am out of it. Drawing bicycles is always fun, and this design is especially cool and different from any bike I've ever drawn. It suits Varvara's very short legs ;).</p>
  </p><p><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/uxn.html'>Read more</a>.]]>
  </description>
  </item>


<item>
  <title>FSF Talk</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/fsftalk.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>FSF talk</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/fsftalk/sailing.png" width="600"><p>On March 20th 2022, Devine and I gave a <a href='https://www.fsf.org/news/artist-collective-hundred-rabbits-to-keynote-libreplanet-living-liberation' target='_blank'>keynote talk</a> for <a href='https://libreplanet.org/2022/' target='_blank'>Libre Planet 2022</a>. See the <a href='https://media.libreplanet.org/u/libreplanet/m/software-doldrums/' target='_blank'>video</a>.</p>
    <p>The drawings featured in the presentation were drawn by hand, in ink, photographed, lightly processed in GIMP and included in <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/adelie.html' target='_blank'>Adelie</a>, our slideshow program.</p><p>We talked about living on the water, often away from civilization, internet connection and distribution routes, how we could not bring our digital creations to life without the capability to repair devices and fix software ourselves, and how this led us to making our own software.</p><p>I was a bit nervous, but it went well. It is easier to talk to a laptop than to a crowd, and it is also easier knowing that my face isn't up on a screen somewhere (ha).</p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/fsftalk/sketchbook.jpg" width="600">
  </p><p><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/fsftalk.html'>Read more</a>.]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Rabbits cutting wood</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderrabbits.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Rabbits cutting wood</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/wunderland/wunderland.8.full.png" width="600"><p>Rabbits cutting some wood.</p>
  </p><p><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderrabbits.html'>Read more</a>.]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Uxn and Varvara</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/uxn.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Uxn and Varvara</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/uxn/09.full.png" width="600"><p>I made a new illustration of Uxn and Varvara together. Hand-drawn, inked and photographed, processed in Gimp (changed positions a bit). <a href='https://nchrs.xyz/site/home.html' target'_blank'>Rostiger</a> drew some <a href='https://merveilles.town/@rostiger/107724702555868632' target='_blank'>amazing art of Uxn</a>(Mastodon), and it made me want to draw them too!</p>
    <img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/uxn/09.photo.jpg" width="600">
  </p><p><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/uxn.html'>Read more</a> about Uxn.]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Hitobito</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/hitobito.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Hitobito</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/hitobito/118.jpg" width="400"><p>I finally added all of the Hitobito drawings on kokorobot! Previously, the art was hosted on Tumblr and I never liked that. It took a while for me to do transfer everything because I had 137 drawings to download, label, and sort through. Now it is done, forever and I am glad.</p>
    <p>This project spanned 2012-2014 (on an off) and spanned 4 countries.</p>
  </p><p><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/hitobito.html'>Read more</a> about Hitobito.]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Yufo</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/yufo.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Yufo</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/yufo/screenshot1.jpg" width="500"><p>Devine & I submitted <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/yufo.html'>Yufo</a> to the <a href='https://itch.io/jam/virtual-pet-jam' target='_blank'>2022 Virtual Pet Jam</a>. Yufo likes rock, paper, scissors, and ramen. It's a simple game that you're meant to keep on in the background as you do other tasks. Yufo has a short lifespan, and depending what you give/withhold, and how often, their appearance changes as they age</p><p>We're getting better at making projects in <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/uxn.html'>Uxn</a>, and this little desktop toy is proof of that. The game isn't as complex and as it could be, but it was fun to make.
  </p><p><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/yufo.html'>Read more</a> about Yufo.]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Morse logo</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/illustration.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Le Morse</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/illustration/lemorseweb.jpg" width="516"><p>I just finished a Morse(walrus) logo for <a href='https://lemorse.quebec/' target='_blank'>Le Morse</a>(French), an ethical web design studio (Studio de conception web éthique). The logo was conceptualized on paper, and then drawn in <a href='https://100r.co/site/nasu'>Nasu</a>. The logo base is small, but because it is pixel art it is lossless and can be scaled up to infinity without losing resolution (fun!). I process my images in GIMP, and when scaling up at image I make sure to scale it using multiples of 8 and to select 'none' in the interpolation dropdown menu. It was my first time making a logo destined for print in Nasu. The final image is a PNG, which is lighter than an SVG and still works on older browsers. I also handed them a <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/chr_format.html' target='_blank'>.CHR file</a>, so the art can be edited in any NES editor.</p>
    <img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/illustration/lemorseweb.2.jpg" width="624">
    <p>I am so glad Hugo asked me to collaborate, because I care a lot about energy-use online, as well as content clarity, and accessibility on the internet. The studio website is not finished yet, but soon!</p>
    <p>Another similar project I like is <a href='https://www.pikselkraft.com/' target='_blank'>Pikselkraft</a>(French).</p>]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Vancouver Island Mushrooms</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/vanislandmushroom.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Vancouver island mushroom</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>I forgot to add this to my rss (oops), but last month I started a new ink drawing series. British Columbia in Canada (where I am now) is home to many wonderful mushrooms. Vancouver Island in particular, is a great location for learning about and foraging mushrooms. I made this series to learn about local varieties (I'm new to this place), and also because I love getting lost into their details. I love drawing little nubs, bumps and folds  and these mushrooms are perfect.</p>
    <p>I made these while listening to the <a href='https://www.canadaland.com/' target='_blank'>Canadaland</a> podcast <a href='https://www.canadaland.com/shows/the-white-saviors/' target='_blank'>White Saviors</a>, a series about the WE foundation and how the 'savior industry' creates a constant need for victims. I highly recommend it.</p>
    <p>The mushroom series isn't finished yet. Visit the <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/vanislandmushroom.html' target='_blank'>project page</a> to see all of the entries so far.</p>
    <img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/vanislandmushroom/cantharellus_main.jpg" width="500">]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Cat Clock</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/catclock.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Cat clock</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>I designed a custom kit-cat klock utility for <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/uxn.html'>Uxn</a>.</p>
    <p>Visit the <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/catclock' target='_blank'>cat clock repository</a> to learn how to run it.</p>
    <img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/catclock/catclock.gif" width="500">]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Old art</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/notes.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Uxn</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>My website has a lot of newer works, but doesn't include past work. I started to add it all back.</p><p>Looking at my past work made me feel bad about my current work because I am not as prolific today. I have less time to dedicate to drawing now. It is easy to glorify the past, it's easy to feel bad about being less productive, but the truth is that I was sad back then. Drawing was a refuge, a way to populate my life with things I lacked. Yes. I draw less now, but I'm also happier.</p><p>New pages include stuff I did while I was still in school, from <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/physical.html' target='_blank'>the late 90's to 2005</a>, <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/newphysical.html' target='_blank'>physical</a> works like paintings and sculptures, <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/applecarving.html' target='_blank'>apple carvings</a> and old <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/oldart.html' target="_blank">digimon era</a> art (I was into a fictional digimon community during my teen years). I also added a page about <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/drownspire.html' target="_blank">Drownspire</a>, the precusor to <a href='https://100r.co' target='_blank'>Hundred Rabbits</a>. In my <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/rek.html' target='_blank'>about me</a> page, I added details on my involvement in small communities.</p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/oldart/physical/sushichef.jpg" width="500">]]>
  </description>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>Uxn page and uxn icons for itchio</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/uxn.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Uxn</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Added a <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/uxn.html'>page</a> for the Uxn 8-bit computer project I am collaborating on with Devine, featuring the artwork I've done.</p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/uxn/main.jpg" width="500"><p>I am currently re-vamping the <a href='https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/' target='_blank'>itch.io storefront</a> and re-skinning all of the icons for our tools as they are released for the Uxn system. I actually finished them all :), but will only share them once the Uxn ports are complete. So for now, here are the icons for Orca and Nasu! The idea was to make de-evolved forms of the rabbit mascots, and to make them look like vegetables.</p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/illustration/illustration.tools.full.jpg" width="500">]]>
  </description>
  </item>
<item>
  <title>Wunderland rabbit update</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderrabbits.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Wunderland rabbits</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Some new Wunderland Rabbit travel pics. They went to Patricia bay and Rhodo Ravine. <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderrabbits.html'>Continue Reading</a></p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/wunderland/wunderland.5.full.jpg" width="600"><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/wunderland/wunderland.6.full.jpg" width="600">]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Sketchbook</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/sketchbook.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Sketchbook</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Added a sketchbook page, with random works that aren't on the main illustration page.<a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/sketchbook.html'>Continue Reading</a></p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/sketch/002.thumb.jpg" width="500">]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Pandoc notes</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/pandoc.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Pandoc</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>I updated my notes on using pandoc to publish e-books to include exports to Epubs and Mobi.<a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/pandoc.html'>Continue Reading</a></p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/interface/pandocpdf.png" width="500">]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Wunderland Rabbits</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderrabbits.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Wunderland Rabbits</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>A photo project of the rabbits Rek and Dev touring Vancouver Island with their good friends, Kay and Rik. Rek & Dev never have photos of themselves together, but Kay sends photos after every trip. It is now tradition for all of Kay's pics to become rabbit tour pics... <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderrabbits.html'>Continue Reading</a></p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/wunderland/wunderland.0.full.jpg" width="500">]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Busy Doing Nothing e-book release</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/busydoingnothing.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Busy Doing Nothing e-book</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Added a page for the released of Busy Doing Nothing, 217-page e-book chronicling daily happenings on the 51-day passage of HundredRabbits from Japan to Canada.</p><p>The original logbook was transcribed, and released online in August 2020. On February 17th 2021, Hundredrabbits released a formatted revised edition for e-readers with extra content.</p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/stories/busydoingnothing/story.busydoingnothing.01.jpg" width="500">]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Uxn mascot</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/illustration.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>uxn mascot</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 1 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Made a mascot for Uxn, a little <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>VM project</a> by Hundredrabbits. Paired the illustration with <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/gyo.html' target='_blank'>Gyo</a>, since I hadn't added it to the website before? And anyway, they look nice together don't they?</p><img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/illustration/illustration.uxngyo.full.jpg" width="500">]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>2020 yearend review</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/2020dec31.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2020 year end review</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<p>Rekka awakens, having forgotten to write a year-end review for the past 6 years. They feel guilty about it, but aren't surprised—this is very typical. They start things and either lose interest, or forget about it entirely.</p><p>Damn shame. But it is what it is.</p><p>Much has changed in the last 6 years, I live on a boat, am genderqueer—well, this isn't new, I've never been entirely comfortable with myself, but this year I was able to reject my impostor syndrome, and started adopting the term—I write more, I sailed to Japan and around the Pacific Ocean, I get fewer anxiety attacks, I've become a bird nerd, learned a lot about living with less and on living closer to nature. Basically, I am now forever ruined, I cannot work for others again.</p><p>The year started in Montreal. In August of 2019, Devine & I left our boat Pino in Japan and flew home to Montreal for 6 months. January marked the 5th month of our sailing hiatus. It was our first time away from the boat, something that's caused me a lot of anxiety, manifesting as nightmares every night. I'd have visions of Pino filled with water, and cockroaches. Horrifying. I did say that I got fewer anxiety attacks this year, and then start by saying I had an anxiety attack. I swear, I got better.</p><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/2020dec31.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Rope mats</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/rug.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Rope mats</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
    <![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/rug/smallmat.jpg" width="500"><p>I made new two mats, a small one, that can be used as a coaster, or as cushioning for blocks (for sailing), and an elongated one for our stairs.</p><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/rug.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Conversion charts</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/conversion.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Conversion charts</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Metrication in Canada began in 1970, but today, there is still use of non-metric units in everyday life. The reason for this, is due to the country's historical ties to the UK, and because of its proximity to the US.</p>

<p>Much of the english content on the internet is by American users who use the Imperial system. I find myself converting recipe volumes, and measurements almost everyday. I saved this table to help me convert with ease, without resorting to online calculators.</p><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/conversion.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ocean plait mat tutorial</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca/site/rug.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>Ocean plait mat tutorial</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 7 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/rug/3.jpg" width="500"></a> <p>One of the best ways to make use of old rope is to work up a set of rope mats. I made this mat using a 12 mm (1/2") old 35-meter (115 ft) main halyard, making a 6-pass Napoleon knot with a Flemish coil around it. The ropes were stitched together in the end so the mat would keep its shape.</p><p>I made a tutorial to show others how to make it.</p><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/rug.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
</channel></rss>