<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?><rss version='2.0' xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'><channel>

<title>Rek Bell</title>
<link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
<description>Journal of Rek</description>
 <image>
<url>https://kokorobot.ca/media/services/rss.jpg</url>
<title>Journal of Rek</title>
<link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
</image>

<item>
  <title>Kaizah</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<![CDATA[<p>I finished the <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html">Hakum</a> sequence <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/kaizah.html">Kaizah</a>. I'm pleased with the result! I also went over a lot of the comics in the <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum_archive.html">Hakum Archive</a>, as I've said before they are no longer canon, but I did update some of the text anyway to bring them more in line. The handwritten text wasn't easy to read, so I updated all of them with the font I made(see <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/making_a_font.html">Making a font</a>). I also published an older short sequence I had finished named <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/aftermath.html">Aftermath</a> that follows <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/night_terror.html">Night Terror</a>, a short comic to show that Dae and Seir have a really difficult relationship.</p>

<p>I released a new <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/wunderland_13_full.jpg">Wunderland Rabbits</a> image. Spring is here on the West Coast of Canada, camas plants are in full bloom. We are getting ready to depart for northern waters, filling the boat with food, gathering e-books, etc.</p>

<p>Because I am learning <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/modern_standard_arabic.html">Modern Standard Arabic</a> on the side, I've started keeping notes! I will append to this page as I go.</p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Splash</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<![CDATA[<p>My website now has a splash page! Hovering the cursor over characters reveals little speech bubbles, it's possible to click on those and it'll take you somewhere on this site. If ever clicking/hovering on the image doesn't occur to people, I also added a re-direct that kicks in after 10 seconds.</p>

<p>I am still working on the new comic sequence for <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html">Hakum</a>. Unlike previous releases, where I would publish pages as I finished them, I will publish them all at once. Here is a <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/hakum_preview_240404.jpg" target="_blank">sneak peek</a>.</p>

<p>A few months ago I bought some mochigome(sticky Japanese rice) with the goal of learning how to make mochi. It took me a long time to try because I wasn't sure it was possible to do by hand on the boat. Most tutorials require the use of powered appliances. I've seen Japanese do it by hand by rapidly beating the dough with a mallet, I knew I couldn't do exactly that, but I had a pestle. I cooked the rice, transferred the rice to a bowl, crushed the rice with a potato masher, then went to work beating the dough using my pestle. It's hard work, it took me around 15 minutes of constant beating to get it to a sticky, cohesive mass. Then, I used plenty of cornstarch to separate the dough into 10 balls. Devine & I later cooked the balls with roasted sesame oil in a pan. The result was rice cakes that were crunchy on the outside, and soft and sticky on the inside. We'll make mochi again for sure, maybe next time we'll try to stuff the sticky dough with sweet red beans(anko). See <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/galley_experiment_mochi.jpg" target="_blank">the result</a>.</p>

<p>I made another small <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/rope_mats.html">rope mat</a> for <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/pino.html">Pino</a> earlier this month. The <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/ropemats_blackrug.jpg">little black mat</a> was even featured in the latest hundred rabbits <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/videos/march_2024.jpg" target="_blank">newsletter</a>(without the flemish coil). If you're wondering what Little Ninj is doing in the image, he is trying to flatten the mat. When a new mat is finished it won't be comfortable to step on because the ropes are still round, but if the mat is set on the floor, time and the passing of feet will flatten it out. Stamping on a mat repeatedly is a quick way to flatten it, it's also possible to use a rubber mallet. Generally, we tolerate the initial discomfort and wait for the material to settle on its own.</p>

<p>In the interest of conserving useful articles about boating/sailing, I mirrored two articles on my website: <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/defensive_boating.html" target="_blank">defensive boating</a> and <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/gunwale_and_hull_cushioning.html" target="_blank">gunwale and hull cushioning</a>.</p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Knots</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<![CDATA[<p>I added instructions on how to make small <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/rope_mats.html">rope mats</a>, the images are at the end of the post. I also shared instructions on how to make <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/a_good_friction_hitch.html">a good friction hitch</a>. Yep, I've been getting back into knotting lately! I documented some of the <a href="https://100r.co/site/knots.html" target="_blank">knots</a> that Dev & I use the most aboard <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/pino.html">Pino</a> on the 100r website.</p>

<p>I improved the look of the <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html">Hakum</a> page, adding small graphics and trying to space out the content better to make it more pleasant to read (I have a tendency to pack a lot of text in a single page *sweats*). I started a new comic sequence but progress is slow because Dev & I are preparing for a big sailing trip this summer. We hope to make it to Northern B.C., near the Alaskan border. I spend my days studying guide books and charts, trying to understand how the wind and current behaves. This coast is not easy to sail, but we want to get better acquainted with it, even if it means getting uncomfortable for a short while.</p>]]>
</description>
</item>


<item>
  <title>Network of Trust</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<![CDATA[<p>February 14th marks my 8th year living aboard <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site//pino.html>Pino</a>! The boat is doing well, although Dev & I both suffered a cold these past few days. We are two disgusting snot fountains.</p>

<p>Because it is becoming harder and harder to find good information on the internet by way of search engines, I overhauled my list of <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/bookmarks">bookmarks</a>, documenting my favorite websites and resources to try and combat AI garbage generators and websites that spin content. Building lists of trusted links written by experienced and well-meaning humans, and hosting them on your website, is a good way to create a network of trust.</p>

<p>I completed <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/ruler_of_the_taiga.html">Ruler of the Taiga</a>. It is annoying how even if I just completed <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/night_terror.html">Night Terror</a>, I already dislike a lot of the art. My hand and my eye keeps improving, it's a good thing but it makes it difficult to appreciate work now that I was proud of at the time of completion. The spell wears off so quickly. I am glad I am improving, but I hate being this inconsistent. I've always assumed that once I learned to draw that I could only get better at it, that regressing was not possible, but if there are too many long lulls between drawing sessions(months, years...) I realized that it is possible to lose it. The skill isn't lost entirely, but the work can appear stiff. Drawing will always make me happy, but I hope that my work eventually stabilizes. Note that this 'regression' is only true when drawing characters with realistic proportions (projects like <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html">Hakum</a>, and <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/circa.html">Circa</a>), errors are more apparent in designs like this than with a project with a cartoon style like <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/mindbird.html">mindbird</a>.</p>

<p>I did a few <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/sprite.html">sprite</a> commissions, see <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_43_full.jpg">Alex P.</a>, <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_44_full.jpg">Benji and family(1)</a>, and <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_45_full.jpg">Benji(2)</a>.</p>

<p>I made some modifications to <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/rope_mats.html">rope mats</a>, so that intructions are clearer. I made a tiny mat out of red paracord for a friend this month for v-day, I missed making mats, I plan to make more this month.</p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>New old art</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>https://kokorobot.ca/site/home.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[

<p>Wahoo! <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/night_terror.html">Night Terror</a> is finished! Currently sketching a new sequence which I look forward to sharing :>!</p>

<p>I did a few <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/sprite.html'>sprite</a> commissions this month, see <a href="https://kokorobot.ca//media/content/project/sprite/sprite_42_full.jpg">Alex</a>, <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_41_full.jpg">Squid</a>, and <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_40_full.jpg">Sofia</a>.</p>

<p>I added a bunch of new(old) production art to <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/uno.html'>uno</a> and <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/wiktopher.html'>wiktopher</a>. I'm trying to gather all of my art on this website, even the really old stuff (see <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/old_art.html'>old art</a>). I logged into DeviantArt the other day and saw how they had fully intergrated AI into their platform, which makes me so, so sad. As HelveticaBlanc said so well in a <a href="https://merveilles.town/@helveticablanc/111769636001496627" target="_blank">recent toot</a>(Mastodon): <i>"I don't wanna see AI in any form, even as a joke. It's a nightmare for labor and the environment, an insult to the spirit of art, and I'm fully on the side of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dune_(franchise)#The_Butlerian_Jihad" target="_blank">Butlerian Jihad</a>."</i> Yes, me too. AI art is hollow, it is a grotesque parody of what it is to be human.</p>

<p>I've had two accounts parked on DA for the longest time (@esserawks and @mintenko), I kept them for memory's sake, but after seeing what DA has become I've decided to deactivate them. All of my art lives on this page now.</p>]]>
</description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>