<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?><rss version='2.0' xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'><channel>

<title>Rek Bell</title>
<link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
<description>Journal of Rek</description>
 <image>
<url>https://kokorobot.ca/media/services/rss.jpg</url>
<title>Journal of Rek</title>
<link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
</image>

<item>
  <title>Network of Trust</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<![CDATA[<p>February 14th marks my 8th year living aboard <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site//pino.html>Pino</a>! The boat is doing well, although Dev & I both suffered a cold these past few days. We are two disgusting snot fountains.</p>

<p>Because it is becoming harder and harder to find good information on the internet by way of search engines, I overhauled my list of <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/bookmarks">bookmarks</a>, documenting my favorite websites and resources to try and combat AI garbage generators and websites that spin content. Building lists of trusted links written by experienced and well-meaning humans, and hosting them on your website, is a good way to create a network of trust.</p>

<p>I completed <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/ruler_of_the_taiga.html">Ruler of the Taiga</a>. It is annoying how even if I just completed <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/night_terror.html">Night Terror</a>, I already dislike a lot of the art. My hand and my eye keeps improving, it's a good thing but it makes it difficult to appreciate work now that I was proud of at the time of completion. The spell wears off so quickly. I am glad I am improving, but I hate being this inconsistent. I've always assumed that once I learned to draw that I could only get better at it, that regressing was not possible, but if there are too many long lulls between drawing sessions(months, years...) I realized that it is possible to lose it. The skill isn't lost entirely, but the work can appear stiff. Drawing will always make me happy, but I hope that my work eventually stabilizes. Note that this 'regression' is only true when drawing characters with realistic proportions (projects like <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html">Hakum</a>, and <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/circa.html">Circa</a>), errors are more apparent in designs like this than with a project with a cartoon style like <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/mindbird.html">mindbird</a>.</p>

<p>I did a few <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/sprite.html">sprite</a> commissions, see <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_43_full.jpg">Alex P.</a>, <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_44_full.jpg">Benji and family(1)</a>, and <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_45_full.jpg">Benji(2)</a>.</p>

<p>I made some modifications to <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/rope_mats.html">rope mats</a>, so that intructions are clearer. I made a tiny mat out of red paracord for a friend this month for v-day, I missed making mats, I plan to make more this month.</p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>New old art</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>https://kokorobot.ca/site/home.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[

<p>Wahoo! <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/night_terror.html">Night Terror</a> is finished! Currently sketching a new sequence which I look forward to sharing :>!</p>

<p>I did a few <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/sprite.html'>sprite</a> commissions this month, see <a href="https://kokorobot.ca//media/content/project/sprite/sprite_42_full.jpg">Alex</a>, <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_41_full.jpg">Squid</a>, and <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_40_full.jpg">Sofia</a>.</p>

<p>I added a bunch of new(old) production art to <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/uno.html'>uno</a> and <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/wiktopher.html'>wiktopher</a>. I'm trying to gather all of my art on this website, even the really old stuff (see <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/old_art.html'>old art</a>). I logged into DeviantArt the other day and saw how they had fully intergrated AI into their platform, which makes me so, so sad. As HelveticaBlanc said so well in a <a href="https://merveilles.town/@helveticablanc/111769636001496627" target="_blank">recent toot</a>(Mastodon): <i>"I don't wanna see AI in any form, even as a joke. It's a nightmare for labor and the environment, an insult to the spirit of art, and I'm fully on the side of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dune_(franchise)#The_Butlerian_Jihad" target="_blank">Butlerian Jihad</a>."</i> Yes, me too. AI art is hollow, it is a grotesque parody of what it is to be human.</p>

<p>I've had two accounts parked on DA for the longest time (@esserawks and @mintenko), I kept them for memory's sake, but after seeing what DA has become I've decided to deactivate them. All of my art lives on this page now.</p>]]>
</description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>