<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?><rss version='2.0' xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'><channel>

<title>Rek Bell</title>
<link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
<description>Journal of Rek</description>
 <image>
<url>https://kokorobot.ca/media/services/rss.jpg</url>
<title>Journal of Rek</title>
<link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
</image>

<item>
  <title>Stormy seas</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<p>This past month has been very stormy, and when I say this I mean that the recent weather in the Salish Sea has been a bit crazy of late(lots of 40-60 kt wind days), but also that I am witnessing a real life <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Idiocracy" target="_blank">Idiocracy</a> in the making. It's not all bad though, it was a very productive month!</p>

<p><b>ART</b>. I illustrated some <a href="../media/content/stream/salmonlice2_1200.jpg">Atlantic Salmon and a Sea Louse</a> for a presentation at <a href="https://masts.ac.uk/annual-science-meeting/" target="_blank">MASTS's</a> Annual Science Meeting about the effects of salmon farms on the wider ecosystem. The drawings will also appear in the <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.05502" target="_blank">accompanying paper</a>! It is my first time contributing to a scientific paper, and that's pretty neat (I was even assigned an Erdős number).<br><a href="https://100r.co/site/rabbit_waves.html" target="_blank">Rabbit Waves</a> was announced officially! I've since released two more pages, one about Morse Code and another on using flags to signal Morse Code. The project was well received, I got a lot of good comments. Devine & I put a lot of care into making the website accessible to people with screen readers (thank you Rembrand for your helpful feedback on this).</p> 

<p><b>BOOKS</b>. This month I've been reading yet another Arthur Conan Doyle book aloud to Devine, The Memoirs of Sherlock Holmes. As always, it is a very entertaining read. I enjoy that perpetrators are not always prosecuted, sometimes people commit crimes out of desperation, or are victims of an unfortunate series of events, Holmes, despite collaborating with officials, is a very fair man(a rare quality).</p>

<p><b>TRICKS</b>. I use YouTube often but I despise the interface, but I found a solution! I installed <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/untrap-for-youtube/" target="_blank">Untrap</a>, a Firefox add-on. I turned off suggested videos, shorts, likes, comments, and tons of others buttons and distraction-ware on mine. My homepage is now just a blank page with a search bar — total bliss!<br>I stitched a pair of <a href="../site/sewing.html">arm warmers</a> for myself and for Devine to keep our hands warm. I used to wear arm warmers all the time as a teen, but never thought of making my own until now.</p>

<p><b>MENTAL HEALTH</b>. I added a page on my site called {happynothappy}, which is just a very simple way to track how I feel from day to day. It would be more beneficial to track reasons as to why I feel a certain way on certain days, but for now I just want to keep it simple, otherwise I run the risk of abandoning the whole endeavour. <a href="https://nchrs.xyz/" target="_blank">Rostiger</a> made their own <a href="https://git.sr.ht/~rostiger/happyNotHappy" target="_blank">version</a> of my very basic tracker, which is a thousand times superior to mine, hehe!</p>

<p><b>MOVIES</b>. I saw the Rocky Horror Picture Show for the first time ever at the Vic Theater on October 27th. Of course, having never seen the film, most of the memes were lost on me, but thankfully I had read about what to expect so it was not too shocking to receive pieces of cooked toast and rice on my head. Tim Curry is absolutely brilliant in this role! He has such an amazing command of his expressions, it is evident that he has a background in theater. Luckily, I can watch the film again and again on my own because it is available for download on <a href="https://archive.org/details/rockyhorrorpictureshow">archive.org</a>.<br>I also watched 2 french comedies I hadn't previously seen: 3 Hommes et Un Couffin by Coline Serreau(same person who directed the amazing La Belle Verte), and Bienvenue chez les Ch'tis by Dany Boon. The storylines of both films were predictable, but still very enjoyable(more so than their English counterparts).</p>

<p><b>QUOTES</b><q>If you think technology will solve your problems, you don’t understand technology — and you don’t understand your problems.</q><cite>A quote by Laurie Anderson</cite></p>

<p><b>CALL TO ACTION</b> Trans people in the US are not likely to get support now that the orange man is back in power, and it is likely that some of the rhetoric will spill over our side of the border. There are many organizations that exist to improve queer, trans, and Two-Spirit lives in Canada. You can find organizations in your area using the <a href="https://egale.ca/rainbow-action-hub/#tab-local" target="_blank">Rainbow Action Hub</a> on Egale's website. I've recently donated a binder to <a href="https://qmunity.ca/about/" target="_blank">Qmunity</a> in Vancouver.<br>If you recall, I recently shared Given and C.C.'s gofundme page, their funding target was reached and the campaign has ended, but they still need help. They will continue to share updates on <a href="https://ko-fi.com/ccohanlon" target="_blank">Kofi</a>, support them there if you can.</p>

<p><b>ARTICLES I READ AND LIKED</b></p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://entomologytoday.org/2024/11/11/entomologists-call-action-fight-disinformation-shawn-otto-entomology-2024/" target="_blank">Entomologists Get a New Call to Action in the Fight Against Disinformation</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.anildash.com/2024/11/19/dont-call-it-a-substack/" target="_blank">Don't call it a Substack</a></li>
</ul>

<p><b>GREAT WEBSITES/PROJECTS</b></p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.guerrillagirls.com/" target="_blank">Guerilla Girls</a>, the website of the anonymous artist activists & feminists known as the Guerilla Girls.</li>
  <li><a href="https://palomakop.tv/zine-club/" target="_blank">Zine Club</a>, sign up to receive zines and/or mystery objects, handcrafted by multimedia artist Paloma Kop, in the mail.</li>
  <li><a href="https://vimeo.com/377457558" target="_blank">RJ</a>, a re-enactment of Hanna Weiner's flag semaphore version of Romeo and Juliet.</li>
</ul>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Shades of Bacchus!</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Hello all! In the 1934 film It's A Gift, a brat drops grapes on a man's face, after which he shouts "Shades of Bacchus!" Bacchus is the god of wine in Roman mythology. Dev & I heard this said in the 4th season of What we Do in the Shadows, said by the energy vampire Colin Robinson in a moment that doesn't involve wine or grapes, merely to express surprise, but we loved this saying so much that we have since adopted it. And now, your life too has been enriched by having learned that this expression exists.<br>Now on to the updates of the month!</p>

<p><b>WEBSITE NEWS</b>. This website now has a <b>light mode</b>! I should have implemented this ages ago, all of my other websites have a light/dark mode, but now it's done! If your browser preferences are set for light mode, you'll see it. The default is still the dark mode, because it's what my eyes prefer.<br>In other website-related news, I wrote a post called <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/keeping_teeth_healthy.html" target="_blank">keeping teeth healthy</a>. I was hesitant to share it publicly because I was embarrassed to admit of being bad at taking care of my teeth, but I got a lot of support from others who suffered the same problems. Body maintenance is difficult, I ought not to be embarrassed about it, I will likely continue to learn how to do things better till I die.</p>

<p><b>SAILING</b>. Pino is back on the Victoria docks. I was looking forward to it this year, I was glad to have access to water on tap again. In the summer, water in the Salish Sea is a rare commodity, we have to use it like the precious resource that it is. This translates to not doing laundry, and by not taking quality showers aboard for 5 months. The water in our tanks is for drinking, and for cleaning dishes only(when water is especially low, I usually use a pressure sprayer and do the dishes in the cockpit). After a summer of hard sailing, Pino is a damn mess. I've already cleaned the gunk out of the quarter berth and galley, but each space needs a good exorcism.<br>Being back near a city also means that Dev & I can <a href="https://100r.co/site/store.html#stickers" target="_blank">ship stickers</a> again! I've put items in my <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/store.html" target="_blank">store</a> back online(still selling some mushroom drawings). Devine found a spirograph set for 5$ at a thrift store, we now make intricate patterns on all of the letters that we ship!</p>

<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/stream/2024_spiro.jpg"/>

<p><b>ART</b>. I bought myself a set of coloring pencils! I got them specifically for the <a href="https://rabbitwaves.ca" target="_blank">Rabbit Waves</a> project, for illustrations that need a touch of color. I am creating content for it almost everyday! The project is not released yet, but it'll be out before the end of the month.<br>The bird in the drawing below is a long-billed murrelet, a bird that hangs around the east coast of Russia and Northern Japan. I have never seen this particular type of murrelet, but I have seen Kittlitz's murrelets while sailing in Southeast Alaska. They are such beautiful, tiny birds! They are like small compact auks, measuring about 25 cm (9.8 in). Yes, rabbit waves will have rabbits, but also plenty of seabirds.</p>

<img src="https://kokorobot.camedia/content/stream/2024_ics.jpg"/>

<p><b>FONT</b>. I fixed a few issues with the font for <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/hakum.html" target="_blank">Hakum</a>. Had bad kerning between n & l (the word only comes up a <b>lot</b>). I also moved the apostrophe, hyphen, and the plus sign higher. The font is still not 100% perfect, I fix it when I find the time. I'd also really like to add glyphs for french(é è ê) at some point. See <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/making_a_font.html" target="_blank">Making a Font</a>. I didn't have time to work on Hakum at all this month, I am sad about this, but I'm prioritizing rabbit waves at the moment.</p>

<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/stream/2024_font.jpg"/>

<p><b>BOOKS</b>. I finished reading Andy Weir's Project Hail Mary. I did not expect to like this book so much, the Martian was ok, but this book isn't only about solving problems in a hostile environment(space), it's also about camaraderie. It is difficult to explain why I loved the book without spoiling it, but I will say that the main character's encounter with Rocky really makes this book shine.</p>

<p><b>MOVIES</b>. I learned that Boots Riley, the director/screenwriter of Sorry to Bother You, a film that I loved, had also recently directed the series <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%27m_a_Virgo" target="_blank">I'm a Virgo</a>. I finally got around to watching it, and holy crap...it is very, very good! The characters were well-crafted, the world was fun and created with purpose(to talk about corporatocracy, oppression and exploitation). Then there's Parking Tickets, a fictional animated TV show within the I’m a Virgo universe. Parking Tickets is dark, it grips you and doesn't let go. I enjoyed reading about the show within a show in this <a href="https://www.awn.com/animationworld/mystery-meat-media-unpacks-im-virgo-animation-and-meta-understanding-audiences" target="_blank">article</a>.<br>I watched <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rRkph6XdzYc" target="_blank">Yintah</a>, a CBC documentary following indigenous land defenders in a decade-long fight to keep fossil fuel companies from building pipelines on their traditional lands. Watching this I was completely disgusted at the hypocrisy and barrage of lies coming out of the mouths of Canadian Government officials, pipeline workers and the police/RCMP. Their eyes are set on resource extraction and nothing will keep them from achieving their goals, Indigenous people know that better than anyone.<br>Reconciliation is a word that is thrown around to appease voters, it's an illusion, behind the curtain the Canadian Government is still using century-old tactics to remove Indigenous people from their lands.</p>
<p><i>"I want to buy your horse," an American settler says to an indigenous man. "No, I want to keep my horse," the indigenous man says. Dissatisfied with this response, hellbent on getting the man's horse, the settler goes to another indigenous man, "I want to buy <b>that</b> horse," he says, asking permission from someone who doesn't have the authority to give that horse away.</i></p>
<p>This short skit illustrates well how land was seized in the past, and what is still done today when governments want something from Indigenous people. A few weeks ago, I finished reading I Will Fight No More Forever by Merrill D. Beal, documenting how the American settlers displaced the Nez Perces from their lands. Back in 1877, Chief Joseph too was suffering the lies of government officials: "It makes my heart sick when I remember all the good words and all the broken promises." Good words do not last long unless they amount to something.</p>

<p><b>QUOTES</b><q>I have carried a heavy load on my back ever since I was a boy. I learned then that we were but few while the white men were many, and that we could not hold our own with them. We were like deer. They were like grizzly bears. We had a small country. Their country was large. We were contented to let things remain as the Great Spirit Chief made them. They were not; and would change the mountains and rivers if they did not suit them.</q><cite>A quote by Chief Joseph</cite></p>

<p><b>MUSIC</b>. I am head over heels for the techno mix <a href="https://on.soundcloud.com/RsqQqZcBy12favzw5" target="_blank">BEHEĀDER - LA FORZA</a>. I have a strange relationship with music, songs affect me deeply, beautiful voices and arrangements have the power to bring me to tears. Devine sent me an article called <a href="https://academic.oup.com/scan/article/11/6/884/2223400?login=false" target="_blank">Brain connectivity reflects human aesthetic responses to music</a>, which sets out to explain how certain individuals have strong emotional reactions to music.</p>

<p><b>CALL TO ACTION</b>. Given and C.C., two bright stars are struggling to stay afloat. Circumstances have compelled them to live nomadically. They lack a legal residence anywhere and have neither pensions nor access to banking, social support or medical services. They make due with meagre finances and fend off the increasing pressures of age (C.C. turns 70 this year) and chronic illness. I have donated to their cause many times, but support from many more people would help them ensure that they can continue to get prescription medicines, medical care, as well as the basic requirements of keeping an old boat — their home — afloat for a longer chunk of time, which in turn will help alleviate some stress. <a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/a-voyage-in-search-of-home" target="_blank">Give what you can</a>.</p>

<p><b>ARTICLES I READ AND LIKED</b></p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://everest-pipkin.com/teaching/handmadeRSS" target="_blank">Handwriting Your Own RSS Feed</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://thewalrus.ca/collapse-of-self-worth-in-the-digital-age/" target="_blank">The Collapse of Self-Worth in the Digital Age</a><br></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.404media.co/hurricane-helene-and-the-fuck-it-era-of-ai-generated-slop/" target="_blank">Hurricane Helene and the ‘Fuck It’ Era of AI-Generated Slop</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://thecreativeindependent.com/essays/a-soft-manifesto/" target="_blank">A Soft Manifesto</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/boots-riley-talks-about-a-socialist-alternative-for-society/" target="_blank">Boots Riley Talks About a Socialist Alternative for Society</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.fil.org/blog/the-web-isn-t-forever-new-research-findings-from-not-your-parents-web-project" target="_blank">The Web Isn't Forever</a></li>
</ul>

<p><b>GREAT WEBSITES</b></p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://alttextselfies.net/selfies/" target="_blank">Alt-text selfies</a>, a website documenting selfies but in the form of unique and beautifully-written alt-text</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.removed.social/asean-portfolio" target="_blank">Removed  Across SE Asia</a>, a photo series by Eric Pickersgill showing people with their phones digitally removed.</li>
  <li><a href="http://www.douglas-self.com/MUSEUM/museum.htm" target="_blank">The Museum of Retro Technology</a>, a website documenting cool retro tech, like heliographs and optical telegraphs.</li>
</ul>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>September musings</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<p>I'm going to try something new this month, a long-form, highly detailed journal, which chronicles the projects I've done, but also things I am interested in, what I've read, etc. I share a lot of this stuff on Mastodon, but it's a shame that it isn't also present on my website. These thoughts will now live here too. Here we go!</p>

<p><b>SAILING</b>. Where's Pino now? We are anchored on Galiano Island, comfortably nested in the Gulf Islands of British Columbia. We spent time in Melanie Cove earlier this month too. We wanted a taste of summer weather, we got it. Some days were very warm, too warm to hike. Pino will be returning to the Victoria docks in the fall, I look forward to it. I really miss using our sewing machine, I have many projects in mind!</p>

<p>I started to transcribe the entries of the Victoria to Sitka logbook digitally, I've already published <a href="https://100r.co/site/victoria_to_sitka_logbook.html" target="_blank">the first two weeks</a>. As promised, the log features many silly doodles. Silly doodles are my lifeblood. People who have already read through the log told me how much they liked the black-headed gull syndicate, I am glad of it, it was a recurring joke on that trip. Gulls on logs were a common, and welcome sight. I have many more weeks to transcribe, it will take a long while to go through it all!</p>

<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/sketch/log_syndicate.jpg"/>

<p><b>ART</b>. I've been doodling one of my older ocs Shane "Shock" Evans a lot. I used Shane when roleplaying with a friend in the pokemon universe. I'd love to "recycle" this character into another story, albeit with some improvements, because his current personality requires some considerable finessing. I tend to become very attached to my characters. I always end up reusing them in other projects, although sometimes they're so different that it is impossible to know who they stemmed from. Lupen, from my story <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/wiktopher.html" target="_blank"</a>Wiktopher</a>, actually shares Shane's haircut (although Shane wore it first), but they're nothing alike.</p>

<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/oc_shock_together.jpg"/>

<p><b>BOOKS</b>. Earlier this month, I finished reading Arthur Conan Doyle's <b>The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes</b>. I really enjoyed it, while being familiar with the character — I think most of the English speaking world is — it was my first time reading any of his stories. I love Watson’s constant amazement of Holmes’s observation and deducting skills. “My dear Holmes!” He’d often say, awestruck, after hearing Holmes detail the life a client he’d just met with great accuracy. I recommend it, although the fact that he casually takes cocaine was a bit jarring. Taking cocaine was a "hip" thing to do in 19th century England, but mostly because it wasn't well understood. When the dangers of cocaine became known, Arthur C. D. adapted the story, with Watson helping to wean Holmes off the drug. I love that he didn't double down on his character's use of the drug. The author used words that were at times surprising, like saying "he ejaculated" after a character speaks in a sudden manner. The definition of the word when used with speech reads like this: <i>"To throw out, as an exclamation; to utter by a brief and sudden impulse; as, to ejaculate a prayer."</i> Using it to illustrate something said swifty and suddenly is brilliant, I love the image that it summons in my mind(not the one you're thinking of, you silly rabbit). Unfortunately, its use for anything other than "ejecting semen" will forever be strange in modern times.</p>

<p>I am still reading through Don Norman's book <b>The Design of Everyday Things</b>. I've become more observant, and critical, of the objects around me. It is a wonder that so many terrible products end up in people's hands. I learned about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Toyota_Way" target="_blank">The Toyota Way</a>, which is a set of principles that focuses on reducing waste, increasing productivity, and maintaining a high-quality standard, such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muda_(Japanese_term)" target="_blank">Muda (無駄)</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Autonomation" target="_blank">jidoka (自働化)</a>. I created a page on my website named <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/good_enough_arithmetic.html">good enough arithmetics</a>, coined by Don, to remind myself that precision isn't always necessary. When I shared my notes on Mastodon, someone linked an amazing <a href="https://seweverythingblog.com/2020/05/12/the-hand-as-measuring-device/" target="_blank">blog post</a> on how to use your hand as a measuring device to take approximate measurements. I LOVE that idea! I included some fun ASCII art in the documentation to break the monotony. Drawing hands in ASCII was not easy, but it was fun to try! The book is dry at times, but the lessons are invaluable.</p>

<p>As a last mention of books, I will say that I've been reading Andy Weir's Project Hail Mary aloud to Devine every night. The casual format makes it difficult to stop, we are enjoying it so far, although Ryland Grace, the main character, sounds and behaves exactly like the star of Weir's other book Mark Watney (The Martian). I suspect that he injects a lot of himself into his characters.</p>

<p><b>RABBITS</b>. I've got rabbits on the brain. Last August we went walking on a trail on Cortes Island with our friends Rik & Kay, they sent me photos from that walk, which of course, ended up becoming part of the <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderland_rabbits.html">wunderland rabbits</a> project. I am especially pleased with this one. Rabbits in the ferns!</p>

<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/wunderland_14_full.jpg"/>

<p> What I am most happy about is that I found another way to do the dithering. I used to have a local copy of <a href="https://ditherit.com/" target="_blank">Dither-it</a>, and used the Atskinson algorithm to get the look I wanted, but when I switched from <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/vincent.html">Vincent</a> to <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/obi.html">Obi</a> I forgot to clone the repository, when I was working on this picture I didn't have good enough cell coverage to download it. I ended up toying with Krita, and found an option under Filter>Artistic named Index Colors, which does EXACTLY what I want! I can change the colors under Ramps, and the results are just as good as those produced when using Dither-it. Of course, Dither-it is a really neat tool and I will continue to recommend it, but it is neat that Krita can produce similar results(I haven't found an equivalent in Gimp).</p>

<p>Also, maybe it is a bit too early to announce it, but in rabbit-related news I registered a new domain named <a href="https://rabbitwaves.ca" target="_blank">RabbitWaves</a> for a very special project. The site doesn't have much on it yet, it will soon!</p>

<img src="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/rabbitwaves_01.jpg"/>

<p><b>MUSIC</b>. <a href="https://voidxwitch.com/" target="_blank">Voidxwitch</a> released their new single <a href="https://voidxwitch.bandcamp.com/track/beast-of-the-black-hill" target="_blank">The Beast of the Black Hill</a> and it is excellent! This song is dominating my life, I cannot persuade it to leave my head. Give it a listen!<br>Falling in Reverse's <a href="https://youtu.be/hX0lhueeib8?si=L2BP-4y3h6bKOClE" target="_blank">Prequel</a> is also highly addictive. As on the commenters on YouTube so rightly said, "Falling In Reverse is no longer a band, they are an experience."</p>

<p><b>TRICKS N THINGS</b>. I learned that it was possible to use <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/spellbook.html#terminal_calculator">the terminal as a calculator</a> this month. I really wish I had learned this before! I am constantly doing conversions, being able to do it via the command line simplifies thing! Of course, one cannot just type equations in the terminal, it is necessary to summon <b>bc</b> first. BC was already installed on Manjaro, handy!</p>

<p><b>CALL TO ACTION</b>. As you may have heard, Paul Watson, the founder of the Sea Shepherd Conservation Society, was arrested by Danish police. <i>"Danish authorities claim that the arrest was made due to an international arrest warrant issued by Japan, related to his anti-whaling campaigns in the Antarctic more than a decade ago. Paul faces the possibility of extradition to Japan, where he could spend the rest of his life in prison."</i> Protection nature ought not to be a crime. If you can spare some time, <a href="https://www.paulwatsonfoundation.org/freepaulwatson/" target="_blank">sign this petition</a>.</p>

<p>Also, if you can, buy prints/or commmission a human artist that you like. With the use of AI becoming ubiquitous, they need your support right now, more than ever.</p>

<p><b>ARTICLES I READ AND LIKED</b></p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.techpolicy.press/challenging-the-myths-of-generative-ai/" target="_blank">Challenging the myths of generative AI</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.gypsy-traveller.org/blog/sam-worrall-inequality-on-the-cut/" target="_blank">Inequality on the Cut</a><br></li>
</ul>

<p><b>QUOTE</b><q>The productivity myth suggests that anything we spend time on is up for automation — that any time we spend can and should be freed up for the sake of having even more time for other activities or pursuits — which can also be automated. The importance and value of thinking about our work and why we do it is waved away as a distraction. The goal of writing, this myth suggests, is filling a page rather than the process of thought that a completed page represents.</q>
<p>Sourced from <a href="https://www.techpolicy.press/challenging-the-myths-of-generative-ai/" target="_blank">Challenging the myths of generative AI</a>. I thought this was worth sharing, especially considering what has happened with <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/nanowrimo-organizers-classist-and-ableist-to-condemn-ai/" target="_blank">Nanowrimo</a> last month.</p>

<p><b>GREAT WEBSITES</b></p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://marcusthevisual.com/avatar-legend-of-abioye/" target="_blank">Marcus the Visual</a>, and his well-crafted The Last Airbender fan fiction <b>The Legend of Abioye</b>.</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://annas-archive.org/" target="_blank">Anna's Archive</a>, since most mirrors of libgen are now down, Anna's Archive is fighting to keep the lights on.</li>
</ul>]]>
</description>
</item>


<item>
  <title>Room for thought</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<p>Pino and crew arrived back in familiar waters on August 11th, a bit earlier than we had planned, but after many grey months, we were both looking forward to experiencing some form of summer-like weather. We anchored in Von Donop inlet on Cortes Island, a good place to chill out and to get things done.</p>

<p>My mind has been occupied with weather and currents of late, now that we are still, I have room in my head to tackle some difficult problems.</p>

<p>I finished a new comic sequence for <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html" target="_blank">Hakum</a> named <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/smile.html" target="_blank">Smile</a>.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Grey Days</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<p>A month of upwind sailing, fog, and motoring painfully slowly over still waters, the way back south through northern Canada has not been easy. We had to do short hops between anchorages, and often had to stay for 2-3 days at each stop to wait for favorable weather to keep going. {Obi} has not seen much use, grey days, lack of solar power, make working on the computer difficult, so I've been drawing, mostly, and writing in my logbook.</p>

<p>I drew the cast of {Hakum}, when they're a bit <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/hakum_gang_1990.jpg" target="_blank">younger</a>, and then <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/hakum_gang_2000.jpg" target="_blank">older with some new members</a>. I also completed a very short vignette comic named <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/hakum_shoes.jpg" target="_blank">Shoes</a>, Dae spends all his time in the forest, never wears shoes, and never rode a bike before.</p>

<p>Otherwise, Devine & I have resumed work on {Markl}. We hope to publish it on the Playdate along with {Oquonie}. The Playdate has been a good source of entertainment for me while at anchor, I especially enjoyed the game Saturday Edition by Chris Makris.</p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Waves</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<![CDATA[<p>Pino and crew have sailed back to Canada 2 days ago, landing back in Prince Rupert. We'll slowly make our way back south now.</p>

<p>We've traveled many miles, we completed a loop through Southeast Alaska, passing close to the mainland through Wrangell, Petersburg, and then through Frederick Sound to Sitka, then down down down on the outside waters of Baranof and Dall Island, through Dixon Entrance and into port at Prince Rupert. Sailing in outer waters was lovely, especially on the first day, the sea was smooth, as was the wind, I saw a ton of wildlife. I saw black-footed albatrosses, the last time I saw them was on our Japan to Canada sail in 2020, they are large brown birds with dramatic markings around their eyes, locking their expression into one of constant mourning. As Pino sailed by the Hazy Islands, I saw my first puffin! The Hazy Islands are far offshore, away from traffic and human encroachment, boats can't land there, neither can planes, it's a perfect place for birds, they have a world of their own out there.</p>

<p>The second offshore leg was not as lovely, with big waves at our stern, strong winds, too. "Don't take me again," I said to the sea, "please don't." I kept one hand on the tiller, the other gripped the frame of our roll cage, ready in case the waves decided to misbehave. Further into Dixon Entrance the waves diminished along with any threat of being taken, I was relieved.</p>

<p>I write in my logbook everyday, I don't have creative energy for anything else right now. I draw once in a while, not as often as I'd like. Hopefully, once we get nearer to Vancouver Island, we can find a place to stay put for a few weeks. Yes, weeks, a place with good hiking nearby, a quiet place for deep thinking.</p>

<p>This trip has challenged my strength. I am a human windlass, a haphazard diesel engine mechanic, a nervous wreck at times... but like our strong little ship I too can weather storms.</p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Alaska</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<![CDATA[<p>Just a short update to say that Devine & I have been sailing since May 1st, leaving from Victoria, B.C. We arrived in Ketchikan, Southeast Alaska(US) on June 2nd. We spent all of May moving, taking every weather window we could to make as much progress north as possible. It is tiring, but now that we've arrived a bit higher north we can it a bit slower.</p>

<p>May and June are good months to spend in SE Alaska. It's been very rainy and windy since we've arrived, I'm not sure what nice looks like in these parts... I look forward to it, though. We find cell reception here and there, permitting for updates like this. We'll explore the area, and start making our way back down late July.</p>

<p>I won't be updating this site much in the meantime, maybe just small improvements or notes here and there. Like today, as we are waiting for bad weather to pass in Ketchikan, I worked on the {finic} language. I've got plans for another {Wiktopher} book, so I'm just jotting down ideas. Because I am away, my store is closed, I will put the {Vancouver Island Mushrooms} series back for sale when I return in October. See you then!</p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Kaizah</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<![CDATA[<p>I finished the <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html">Hakum</a> sequence <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/kaizah.html">Kaizah</a>. I'm pleased with the result! I also went over a lot of the comics in the <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum_archive.html">Hakum Archive</a>, as I've said before they are no longer canon, but I did update some of the text anyway to bring them more in line. The handwritten text wasn't easy to read, so I updated all of them with the font I made(see <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/making_a_font.html">Making a font</a>). I also published an older short sequence I had finished named <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/aftermath.html">Aftermath</a> that follows <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/night_terror.html">Night Terror</a>, a short comic to show that Dae and Seir have a really difficult relationship.</p>

<p>I released a new <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/wunderland_13_full.jpg">Wunderland Rabbits</a> image. Spring is here on the West Coast of Canada, camas plants are in full bloom. We are getting ready to depart for northern waters, filling the boat with food, gathering e-books, etc.</p>

<p>Because I am learning <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/modern_standard_arabic.html">Modern Standard Arabic</a> on the side, I've started keeping notes! I will append to this page as I go.</p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Splash</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<![CDATA[<p>My website now has a splash page! Hovering the cursor over characters reveals little speech bubbles, it's possible to click on those and it'll take you somewhere on this site. If ever clicking/hovering on the image doesn't occur to people, I also added a re-direct that kicks in after 10 seconds.</p>

<p>I am still working on the new comic sequence for <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html">Hakum</a>. Unlike previous releases, where I would publish pages as I finished them, I will publish them all at once. Here is a <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/hakum_preview_240404.jpg" target="_blank">sneak peek</a>.</p>

<p>A few months ago I bought some mochigome(sticky Japanese rice) with the goal of learning how to make mochi. It took me a long time to try because I wasn't sure it was possible to do by hand on the boat. Most tutorials require the use of powered appliances. I've seen Japanese do it by hand by rapidly beating the dough with a mallet, I knew I couldn't do exactly that, but I had a pestle. I cooked the rice, transferred the rice to a bowl, crushed the rice with a potato masher, then went to work beating the dough using my pestle. It's hard work, it took me around 15 minutes of constant beating to get it to a sticky, cohesive mass. Then, I used plenty of cornstarch to separate the dough into 10 balls. Devine & I later cooked the balls with roasted sesame oil in a pan. The result was rice cakes that were crunchy on the outside, and soft and sticky on the inside. We'll make mochi again for sure, maybe next time we'll try to stuff the sticky dough with sweet red beans(anko). See <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/galley_experiment_mochi.jpg" target="_blank">the result</a>.</p>

<p>I made another small <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/rope_mats.html">rope mat</a> for <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/pino.html">Pino</a> earlier this month. The <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/ropemats_blackrug.jpg">little black mat</a> was even featured in the latest hundred rabbits <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/videos/march_2024.jpg" target="_blank">newsletter</a>(without the flemish coil). If you're wondering what Little Ninj is doing in the image, he is trying to flatten the mat. When a new mat is finished it won't be comfortable to step on because the ropes are still round, but if the mat is set on the floor, time and the passing of feet will flatten it out. Stamping on a mat repeatedly is a quick way to flatten it, it's also possible to use a rubber mallet. Generally, we tolerate the initial discomfort and wait for the material to settle on its own.</p>

<p>In the interest of conserving useful articles about boating/sailing, I mirrored two articles on my website: <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/defensive_boating.html" target="_blank">defensive boating</a> and <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/gunwale_and_hull_cushioning.html" target="_blank">gunwale and hull cushioning</a>.</p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Knots</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<![CDATA[<p>I added instructions on how to make small <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/rope_mats.html">rope mats</a>, the images are at the end of the post. I also shared instructions on how to make <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/a_good_friction_hitch.html">a good friction hitch</a>. Yep, I've been getting back into knotting lately! I documented some of the <a href="https://100r.co/site/knots.html" target="_blank">knots</a> that Dev & I use the most aboard <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/pino.html">Pino</a> on the 100r website.</p>

<p>I improved the look of the <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html">Hakum</a> page, adding small graphics and trying to space out the content better to make it more pleasant to read (I have a tendency to pack a lot of text in a single page *sweats*). I started a new comic sequence but progress is slow because Dev & I are preparing for a big sailing trip this summer. We hope to make it to Northern B.C., near the Alaskan border. I spend my days studying guide books and charts, trying to understand how the wind and current behaves. This coast is not easy to sail, but we want to get better acquainted with it, even if it means getting uncomfortable for a short while.</p>]]>
</description>
</item>


<item>
  <title>Network of Trust</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[
<![CDATA[<p>February 14th marks my 8th year living aboard <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site//pino.html>Pino</a>! The boat is doing well, although Dev & I both suffered a cold these past few days. We are two disgusting snot fountains.</p>

<p>Because it is becoming harder and harder to find good information on the internet by way of search engines, I overhauled my list of <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/bookmarks">bookmarks</a>, documenting my favorite websites and resources to try and combat AI garbage generators and websites that spin content. Building lists of trusted links written by experienced and well-meaning humans, and hosting them on your website, is a good way to create a network of trust.</p>

<p>I completed <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/ruler_of_the_taiga.html">Ruler of the Taiga</a>. It is annoying how even if I just completed <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/night_terror.html">Night Terror</a>, I already dislike a lot of the art. My hand and my eye keeps improving, it's a good thing but it makes it difficult to appreciate work now that I was proud of at the time of completion. The spell wears off so quickly. I am glad I am improving, but I hate being this inconsistent. I've always assumed that once I learned to draw that I could only get better at it, that regressing was not possible, but if there are too many long lulls between drawing sessions(months, years...) I realized that it is possible to lose it. The skill isn't lost entirely, but the work can appear stiff. Drawing will always make me happy, but I hope that my work eventually stabilizes. Note that this 'regression' is only true when drawing characters with realistic proportions (projects like <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html">Hakum</a>, and <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/circa.html">Circa</a>), errors are more apparent in designs like this than with a project with a cartoon style like <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/mindbird.html">mindbird</a>.</p>

<p>I did a few <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/sprite.html">sprite</a> commissions, see <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_43_full.jpg">Alex P.</a>, <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_44_full.jpg">Benji and family(1)</a>, and <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_45_full.jpg">Benji(2)</a>.</p>

<p>I made some modifications to <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/rope_mats.html">rope mats</a>, so that intructions are clearer. I made a tiny mat out of red paracord for a friend this month for v-day, I missed making mats, I plan to make more this month.</p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>New old art</title>
  <link>https://kokorobot.ca</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>https://kokorobot.ca/site/home.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[

<p>Wahoo! <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/night_terror.html">Night Terror</a> is finished! Currently sketching a new sequence which I look forward to sharing :>!</p>

<p>I did a few <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/sprite.html'>sprite</a> commissions this month, see <a href="https://kokorobot.ca//media/content/project/sprite/sprite_42_full.jpg">Alex</a>, <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_41_full.jpg">Squid</a>, and <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/media/content/project/sprite/sprite_40_full.jpg">Sofia</a>.</p>

<p>I added a bunch of new(old) production art to <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/uno.html'>uno</a> and <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/wiktopher.html'>wiktopher</a>. I'm trying to gather all of my art on this website, even the really old stuff (see <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/old_art.html'>old art</a>). I logged into DeviantArt the other day and saw how they had fully intergrated AI into their platform, which makes me so, so sad. As HelveticaBlanc said so well in a <a href="https://merveilles.town/@helveticablanc/111769636001496627" target="_blank">recent toot</a>(Mastodon): <i>"I don't wanna see AI in any form, even as a joke. It's a nightmare for labor and the environment, an insult to the spirit of art, and I'm fully on the side of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dune_(franchise)#The_Butlerian_Jihad" target="_blank">Butlerian Jihad</a>."</i> Yes, me too. AI art is hollow, it is a grotesque parody of what it is to be human.</p>

<p>I've had two accounts parked on DA for the longest time (@esserawks and @mintenko), I kept them for memory's sake, but after seeing what DA has become I've decided to deactivate them. All of my art lives on this page now.</p>]]>
</description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>